Hello!
Tjena, Douglas.
Sven Billred.
-I have heard that you are going to do a project?
Yes it is true.
-When should it be finished?
Hopefully to Elmia 2019.
It should go.
-Is there any sketch on what it should look like?
Well, most of it is already in the head.
But then I found a picture on the internet on a car.
This one is quite similar.
I will not use any bonnet or screens.
The style itself will be like this with Boat-tail at the back and the front with similar lanterns.
-What do you have for background?
The fact that you have built more cars can prove the wall.
Well, I have built a 1927 Chevrolet that I have used for 10 years.
I also have a Willys from 1939 which was a 4 door that I have built into a coupe.
Exactly after the original.
And that's the only one in Sweden.
There are some Willys Cuper from 1940-41 but they are unusual.
-Cool!
If you are wondering what sounds, it is a fluorescent lamp that creak.
It's an old garage.
I've been here for over 30 years.
It probably needed to be renovated.
-What are you going to build?
It's this car.
From the ground up it is a 1929 chevrolet truck.
-Hher God what a job.
Yes it is a puzzle.
-And everything should be welded and polished.
Yes.
-It will take an hour or two maybe.
Hahaha.
Here is the size of the rear wheel.
There are 17 "rims but it was not in the right size.
So I got to buy these rims and cut up and narrow off the rim so they should fit the tires I bought.
You can see on the inside where the cormorant is.
A snobbring will be mounted so you do not see the welding joint.
It should be founded before I put on the snob bridge.
The rutram and here is the shape of the cab so I'll see how it will be.
All this is made of aluminum that is filled with chemical metal to gain stability.
Then it becomes like a molded piece.
The cab will be glued on this plate.
So you can fold it down like this.
There is a lock on here on top.
It will be a brass plate with keyhole.
And then a spring in stainless steel.
This spring is provisional.
The principle is that you use a spring as a lock.
-You are the man of details.
That's the fun.
You can come up with something then manufacture it.
These are window hooks used on windows on the inside.
It is spring loaded and you can adjust the hardness.
They will be locks for inspection hatches on the engine.
I thought the style fit well.
Most screws and bolts are recessed.
But original was everything riveted.
Then I have turned rivets in brass.
And will be mounted here and glued.
So it looks riveted as it was original.
A therapy work when you are a little tired.
Then you can stand at the lathe and do these.
Only ordinary brass is polished.